Nazia Hasan

nazarah.github.io linkedin.com/in/naziahasan +358405775010 nhasan1987@gmail.com

UX Designer | Product Designer

I aim to align business goals and usage satisfaction while conceptualizing solutions. I enjoy working with developers to harmonize UX & implementation works. I have a **Master's degree** with **UX major** and **7+ years** of experience. I love to face a challenge with empathy, with focus on details and collaboration to solve it. I love strength training, playing with Legos, hiking & cycling.

Skills

Tools

Figma
Sketch
Miro
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Aftereffect
Pen & paper
Microsoft DevOps
Azure APIM
InDesign
Git
Jira

Design

User Research
UI Design
Prototyping
Usability Evaluation
Usage Study
Accessibility
Service Design

Development

HTML
CSS
Low/No coding
OAS3
React gatsby

Others

Stoplight

Developer marketing
Tech blogging
Developer guides & documentations
Product management
SAFe 4.0 frameworks
Finnish B1 - B2

Other Experiences

Keynote Speaking

- 1. API Days Helsinki & North 2022 "Low/No Code Driven Development - winning sales pitch with "WOW EFFECT"
- 2. APIOps Helsinki Meetup, November 2020 "API Documentation & Developer Guide"

Experiences

Design Lead - Concepts & APIs

Platform of Trust Tampere, Finland Jul 2019 - present

Starting as a **DX Developer**, towards being a **Product Manager** and obtaining my current role, my focus is on data servitization and monetization field targeting build environment industry in Finland. My responsibilities are divided between **managing product development** works and ensuring great **Developer experience** for related company products. Currently, I am working on developing a **design system** and **UX guidelines** for existing and upcoming services developed by Platform of Trust.

UI / UX Designer

Sampo Software Oy Tampere, Finland Jun 2016 - Jan 2019

I worked on projects that were diverse from one another in terms of target audiences and key-problem area solutions (API management system, real-time monitoring of biomass equipment, and secured bike storage.) My work spanned from doing user research, wireframing, to creating low/mid fidelity prototypes, interaction model, usability evaluation, and user onboarding materials.

Sr. Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Ohon Tech Ltd. Dhaka, Bangladesh May 2014 - Aug 2014

I took the responsibilities of managing an offshore software quality assurance (SQA) team of a USA based software firm.

SW Business Development Executive

TigerIT Ltd. Dhaka, Bangladesh Oct 2013 - Apr 2014

I worked in the **tender procurement** for government and international ICT projects. I also composed t**echnical documentation** of company products.

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

SoftwarePeople Ltd. Dhaka, Bangladesh Aug 2011 - July 2013

I worked to analyze requirements, prepare and manage test cases, execute manual & automated testing, track bugs, etc.

Nazia Hasan

nazarah.github.io linkedin.com/in/naziahasan +358405775010 nhasan1987@gmail.com

UX Designer | Product Designer

Education

References

(on request)

Tampere University of Technology

Tampere, Finland | 2014 - 2018

Master's in Technology, User Experience

University of Dhaka

Dhaka, Bangladesh | 2005 - 2010

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science & Engineering

Certifications

Interaction Design Foundation (IxDF)

- 1. UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- 2. Conducting Usability Testing

Udemy

- 1. The Complete 'No Code' Developer Course
- 2. REST API Design, Development & Management

Scaled Agile Framework Certification

- 1. SAFe 5.0 Product Owner / Product Manager
- 2. SAFe 4.0 Agilist

Osaango Academy

- 1. Introduction to Data Economy
- 2. Marketing for Developers
- 3. Essential APIs
- 4. Fix Your API Design and Documentation

Yleiset Kielitutkinnot

Yleisten kielitutkintojen suomen kielen keskitason tutkinto.

Code School

1. The Elements of Web Design